

Kelton Ashcraft

SWDAA Co-Member at Large Kappa Kappa Psi

Candidate Packet

Letter of Intent

To the Members of the Southwest District Alumni Association,

I am writing this letter to announce my interest in running again for the position of Co-Member at Large.

This past year, I served on the SWDAA board of directors as KKPsi Co-Member at Large. During my tenure this past year, my main goals were to help further develop the co-member at large position to make it a viable asset for the SWDAA. I have also helped with Striving for Greater Professionals (SFGP) by hosting a talks shop discussion on classroom management and had fun hosting it, as well as communicating with those in the education field.

As an active member, I was heavily involved with my home chapter, Zeta Xi. I held the positions of Historian and Vice president during my studies at Tyler Junior College. I was also honored to be the chapters delegate in the 2012, 2013, and 2014 Southwest District conventions. At those conventions, I was involved with the convention site, membership, and ways & means committees helping to see how to help the progression of the district. I was also a delegate at the 2017 convention in Mesquite when I was a member of Lambda Pi at UT Tyler.

If re-elected as Co-Member at Large, I would do my best to work with the elected Tau Beta Sigma Member at Large to help fulfil the duties outlined in the by-laws as well as expand the role for this position. I would also do my best to help out the other members of the Board of Directors and find different way to reach our alumni. Alumni involvement is an important part of our organization because we spend more time as alumni than as an active member. As the largest district in the organizations, we have a myriad of different alumni across the region and it is important to find way not only to get them involved, but to keep them informed. The same goes for graduating seniors, as they will be heading into uncharted waters of serving the organization from an alumnus perspective. There are many challenges to this, and I feel that it is important for us to motivate and encourage them to continue to serve as alumni.

I want to thank you for your time and consideration. It is an honor to serve.

MLITB.

Kelton Ashcraft

Kelten Ashergh

Fraternal Resume

Local Level

- Zeta Xi Chapter
 - o Initiated Fall 2011
 - o Elected Historian 2012-2013
 - Helped getting our Alumni more involved and informed with the chapter, updated chapter roster and history.
 - o Elected Vice President Spring 2014
- Lambda Pi Chapter
 - o Joined chapter in 2015
 - o Elected Historian Spring 2016

District Level

- Conventions Attended
 - University of Houston 2012
 - o Sam Houston State University 2013
 - o Baylor University 2014
 - \circ Mesquite, Tx 2016
- Area Workshops Attended
 - o 2013 Stephen F. Austin State University

National Level

- Attended National Convention at Oklahoma State University 2019
 - o Performed in the Centennial Alumni Band

Alumni

- Memberships
 - o KKPsi AA
 - o SWDAA
 - Served on Communications Committee 2020
 - Served on Strategic Planning Committee 2020, 2021
 - Served as KKPsi Co-Member at Large 2021-2022

Professional Resume

EDUCATION

- Henderson High School, Henderson, Tx 2010 Graduate
- Tyler Junior College, Tyler, Tx Received Associates in Music Spring 2013
- The University of Texas at Tyler- Received Bachelor's in Music Fall 2018

Major: Music Education

EXPERIENCE

Director of Bands

Mildred ISD - Corsicana, Tx 2020-Present

- Directed all aspects of a 3A band program including recruiting, retention, finances and curriculum
- Taught 6th grade beginners, 7th grade, and 8th-12th band as well as 6th grade Art
- Expanded Color Guard inclusion; group participated in their first winter guard season Spring 2021
- Instructed all rehearsals, sectionals, and lessons
- Maintained all inventory for the program (Instruments, uniforms, supplies, etc.)
- Evaluated and assigned instruments to incoming 6th graders
- Managed multiple budgets as well as fundraisers
 - o Raised over \$1,000 on spirit sock fundraiser, funds helped send band leadership to camp at Texas A&M Commerce
- Participated in all UIL and TMEA/ATSSB events

Assistant Band Director

San Augustine ISD - San Augustine, Tx 2019-2020

- Taught 6th grade beginning music classes
- Ran sectional rehearsals and lessons
- Maintained instrument inventory and musical supplies (reeds, mouthpieces, etc.)
- Instructed Special Education students in classroom setting
- Assigned and prepared students for Solo and Ensemble
- Assessed, evaluated, and assigned students chair placements based on their musical ability

Goals for Office

- Work with the Tau Beta Sigma Member at Large on developing goals and duties for the position of Co-Member at Large.
- Work with the Communications Director on in order to ensure an alumni member or members is present at Area workshops in order to present information on SWDAA.
- Work with the Programs director and TBS Co-Mal on developing ways to promote alumni recruitment and activities.
- Help out directors with projects and activities as needed
- Develop ways in order to inform alumni about SWDAA in an effort to increase membership in the SWDAA.